<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
    <string name="crochet_jellyfish">
        Pattern by ChiWei from One Dog Woof
        \n\n\n
        Supplies
        \n
        \n\t+ G (4mm) hook
        \n\n\t+ Yarnspirations Bernat Handicrafter Cotton Yarn
        \n\t- [2 skeins] Main Color
        \n\t- [1 skein] Secondary Color
        \n\t* The Blue jellyfish is Robin’s Egg Blue and Mod Blue. The Purple jellyfish is Soft Violet and Hot Pink.
        \n\n\t+ 9mm Safety Eyes
        \n\n\t+ Black DMC Embroidery Thread
        \n\n\t+ Embroidery Needle
        \n\n\t+ Scissors
        \n\n\t+ Polyester Fiberfill
        \n\n\n\n
        Instructions:
        \n\n
        Cap/Face
        \n\n
        Round 1: Work 8 sc into a magic circle. Join with sl st to first sc. (8)
        \n\n
        Round 2: Ch 1. Work 2 sc into each stitch around. Join with sl st to first sc. (16)
        \n\n
        Round 3: Ch 1. *Work 1 sc into next stitch, 2 sc into next stitch.* Repeat around. Join with sl st to first sc. (24)
        \n\n
        Round 4: Ch 1. *Work 1 sc into each of next 2 stitches, 2 sc into next stitch.* Repeat around. Join with sl st to first sc. (32)
        \n\n
        Round 5: Ch 1. *Work 1 sc into each of next 3 stitches, 2 sc into next stitch.* Repeat around. Join with sl st to first sc. (40)
        \n\n
        Round 6: Ch 1. *Work 1 sc into each of next 4 stitches, 2 sc into next stitch.* Repeat around. Join with sl st to first sc. (48)
        \n\n
        Round 7-8: Ch 1. Work 1 sc into each stitch around. Join with sl st to first sc. (48)
        \n\n
        Round 9: Ch 1. *Work 1 sc into each of next 5 stitches, 2 sc into next stitch.* Repeat around. Join with sl st to first sc. (56)
        \n\n
        Round 10-14: Ch 1. Work 1 sc into each stitch around. Join with sl st to first sc. (56)
        \n\n
        Round 15: Ch 1. *Work 1 sc into each of next 2 stitches. Work 1 sc2tog, 1 sc into next stitch, 1 sc2tog.* Repeat around. Join with sl st to first sc. (40)
        \n
        Fasten off, and weave in ends.
        \n\n\n
        Jellyfish bottom panel
        \n\n
        Round 1: Ch 1. Work 8 sc into a magic circle. Join with sl st to first sc. (8)
        \n\n
        Round 2: Ch 1. Work 2 sc into each stitch around. Join with sl st to first sc. (16)
        \n\n
        Round 3: Ch 1. *Work 1 sc into next stitch, 2 sc into next stitch.* Repeat around. Join with sl st to first sc. (24)
        \n\n
        Round 4: Ch 1. *Work 1 sc into each of next 2 stitches, 2 sc into next stitch.* Repeat around. Join with sl st to first sc. (32)
        \n\n
        Round 5: Ch 3 (does not count as stitch). *Work 1 dc into each of next 3 stitches, 2 dc into next stitch.* Repeat around. Join with sl st to first sc. (40)
        \n
        Fasten off, but leave a long enough tail to sc around. (Probably a few feet at least).
        \n\n\n
        Jellyfish streamers/tentacles
        \n\n
        I found the streamers were easiest and most fun when done freeform. All of them are a little different, but I used the same basics for each one to maintain consistency. You can check out my curly cue sampler to get an idea of what each type of curl will look like. Also, you can change up the hook size for a different look. I used a G hook for the blue jellyfish and an H hook for the purple jellyfish. On each jellyfish, there are 8 tentacles of varying width and length.
        Chain either 30, 40, 50, 60 or even 70.
        \n
        Work 2 (or 3) sc in each chain stitch OR work 2 (or 3) hdc in each chain stitch. If you’re starting with sc, then work into 2nd chain from hook. If you’re starting with hdc, then work into 3rd chain from hook.
        \n
        Now, think of this as a Choose Your Own Crochet Adventure. Continue working sc or hdc, working 2 or 3 stitches into each chain across, then fasten off, leaving a tail.
        \n
        I found it best if you stick with a particular pattern long enough to establish the right curl, then change it to create a different type curl. Don’t change your stitch type too quickly. You can curl the curly cues properly or leave it messy, up to you\!

        \n\n\n
        Assembly
        \n\n
        Step 1: Attach the safety eyes between rows 12 and 13 on the cap, about 8 stitches apart.
        \n\n
        Step 2:  Use the embroidery thread to sew on a mouth halfway between the eyes.
        \n\n
        Step 3: Attach the tentacles to the bottom panel by weaving both tails of the tentacles through stitch spaces in the panel, and tie a double knot to secure. You can weave the ends in, or maybe not, since it’ll be hidden inside the stuffed head. I chose to weave in ends because I don’t know how hard the kids will pull on the tentacles.
        \n\n
        Step 4: Match up the seam stitch of the panel against the seam stitch of the cap. Insert your hook through both loops (front to back) on one stitch on the cap, and pull through a loop of the panel’s tail. Work a chain stitch. Then insert your hook through the same cap stitch, and through the first stitch on the panel, pull up a loop and complete a sc. (It\’s ok if you fudge this. You just need to attach the two pieces together to get started.)
        \n\n
        Step 5: For the next stitch and for each stitch around, insert hook from outside of cap through all 4 loops (cap and panel). Work a sc.
        \n\n
        Step 6: Once you’ve gone almost around, stuff the head with fiberfill, then continue working sc around to close up the head. Join to the first sc with a sl st. Fasten off and weave in ends.
    </string>
    
    <string name="crochet_blue_whale">
        Pattern by Elisa from Elisa\'s Crochet
        \n\n\n
        Supplies:
        \n
        \n\t+ Medium Weight Yarn in Turquoise and White
        \n\n\t+ 9 mm Black Safety Eyes
        \n\n\t+ 3.5 mm hook
        \n\n\t+ Polyester Fiber Filling

        \n\n\n\n
        Instructions:
        \n\n
        BODY (turquoise and white yarn)
        \n\n
        Round 1: starting off with turquoise yarn, 8 sc in a mr (8)
        \n\n
        Round 2: Inc around (16)
        \n\n
        Round 3: *1 sc, inc*, repeat ** around (24)
        \n\n
        Round 4: *2 sc, inc*, repeat ** around (32)
        \n\n
        Round 5: *3 sc, inc*, repeat ** around (40)
        \n\n
        Round 6: *4 sc, inc*, repeat ** around (48)
        \n\n
        Round 7:  *5 sc, inc*, repeat ** around (56)
        \n\n
        Round 8 - 17: sc even (56); insert the plastic eyes between rounds 15/16, 15 stitches apart
        \n\n
        Round 18: *7 sc, dec*, repeat ** around, 2 sc (50)
        \n\n
        Round 19: switching to white yarn, sc even (50)
        \n\n
        Round 20: working in BLO, *3 sc, dec*, repeat ** around (40)
        \n\n
        Round 21: *2 sc, dec*, repeat ** around (30)
        \n\n
        Round 22: *1 sc, dec*, repeat ** around (20); stuff the doll
        \n\n
        Round 23: dec around (10)
        \n\n
        Round 24: dec around (5); F/O, close the hole and hide the yarn.
        \n\n
        Embroider the 2 LINES under the eyes with some white yarn.


        \n\n\n
        FINS (turquoise yarn; make two)
        \n\n
        Round 1: 5 sc in a mr (5)
        \n\n
        Round 2: inc around (10)
        \n\n
        Round 3: *4 sc, inc*, repeat ** around (12)
        \n\n
        Round 4 - 6: sc even (12)
        \n\n
        Round 7: *4 sc, dec*, repeat ** around (10); F/O and leave a tail of yarn to sew the fin to side of the body.


        \n\n\n
        TAIL (turquoise yarn)
        \n\n
        Make two:
        \n\n
        Round 1: 6 sc in a mr (6)
        \n\n
        Round 2: *2 sc, inc*, repeat ** around (8)
        \n\n
        Round 3: *3 sc, inc*, repeat ** around (10)
        \n\n
        Round 4: *4 sc, inc*, repeat ** around (12)
        \n\n
        Round 5: *5 sc, inc*, repeat ** around (14)
        \n\n
        Round 6: sc even (14)
        \n\n
        Round 7: *5 sc, dec*, repeat ** around (12)
        \n\n
        Round 8: *4 sc, dec*, repeat ** around (10); F/O and cut the yarn
        \n\n
        Do no cut the yarn once you have completed the 2nd fin, CH 1 INSTEAD.
        Merge the two pieces together:
        \n\n
        Round 9: join the yarn with a sl st to the 2nd fin, ch1 and sc in the same st, 3 sc, 1 dec, 4 sc keep crocheting on the other fin, 4 sc, 1 dec, 4 sc (18)
        \n\n
        Round 10: *1 sc, dec*, repeat ** around (12)
        \n\n
        Round 11: sc even (12)
        \n\n
        Round 12: *1 sc, inc*, repeat ** around (18)
        \n\n
        Round 13: *2 sc, inc*, repeat ** around (24); stuff lightly only this part of the tail, do not stuff the two fins
        \n\n
        Round 14: sc even (24); F/O and leave a long tail of yarn to sew the tail to the back of the body (between rounds 18 and 20).


        \n\n\n
        WATER SPRAY (white yarn)
        \n\n
        Round 1: 8 sc in a mr (8)
        \n\n
        Round 2: 8 sc in the bl (8)
        \n\n
        Round 3: *2 sc, dec*, repeat ** around (6)
        \n\n
        Round 4: sc even (6)
        \n\n
        Round 5: 4 sc in each st around (24)
        \n\n
        Round 6: 2 sc in each st around (48); F/O and hide the yarn
        \n\n
        Sew the water spray on top of the whale using some white yarn.
    </string>

    <string name="long_legged_cat">
        Pattern by Kristi Tullus
        \n\n\n
        Supplies:
        \n\n
        \t+ Yarn of your choice.
        \n\n\t+ 2.50 mm Crochet Hook
        \n\n\t+ Polyester Fiberfill
        \n\n\t+ Cotton Embroidery Floss or Yarn for the Eyes and Nose
        \n\n\t+ Yarn Needle
        \n\n\t+ Scissors
        \n\n\t+ Sewing Pins
        \n\n\t+ Stitch Markers

        \n\n\n\n
        Instructions:
        \n\n
        BODY
        \n\n
        Round 1: mr, sc 6  [6]
        \n\n
        Round 2: inc x 6  [12]
        \n\n
        Round 3: (sc, inc) x 6  [18]
        \n\n
        Round 4: (inc, sc 2) x 6  [24]
        \n\n
        Round 5: (sc 3, inc) x 6  [30]
        \n\n
        Round 6-9: sc in each st  [30]
        \n\n
        Round 10: sc, dec, (sc 4, dec) x 4, sc 3  [25]
        \n\n
        Round 11: sc in each st  [25]
        \n\n
        Round 12: (sc 6, dec) x 3, sc  [22]
        \n\n
        Start stuffing the body. Keep adding a bit of fiberfill after every few rounds, stuffing the body firmly.
        \n\n
        Round 13: sc in each st  [22]
        \n\n
        Round 14: sc 2, dec, (sc 5, dec) x 2, sc 4  [19]
        \n\n
        Round 15: sc in each st  [19]
        \n\n
        Round 16: (sc 4, dec) x 3, sc  [16]
        \n\n
        Round 17-19: sc in each st  [16]
        \n\n
        Sl st in next stitch. Fasten off and hide the yarn tail. Finish stuffing.
        Sew the head to the body. I like to use the mattress stitch.
        \n\n
        Add a bit more stuffing before closing the seam.
        \n\n\n
        ARMS (make 2)
        \n\n
        Round 1: mr, sc 6  [6]
        \n\n
        Round 2: inc x 6  [12]
        \n\n
        Round 3: (sc 3, inc) x 3  [15]
        \n\n
        Round 4-6: sc in each st  [15]
        \n\n
        Round 7: (sc 3, dec) x 3  [12]
        \n\n
        Round 8: (sc, dec) x 4  [8]
        \n\n
        Stuff the hands firmly. Do not stuff the arms.
        \n\n
        Round 9-24: sc in each st  [8]
        \n\n
        Sl st in next stitch. Cut the yarn, leaving a long yarn tail for sewing, and fasten off.
        \n\n
        Sew the arms to the sides of the body, one row below the head.
        \n\n
        Cross the arms.
        \n\n
        Then take the arm that\'s on top and bend it, going up under the other one.
        \n\n\n
        LEGS (make 2)
        \n\n
        Round 1: mr, sc 6  [6]
        \n\n
        Round 2: inc x 6  [12]
        \n\n
        Round 3: (sc 2, inc) x 4  [16]
        \n\n
        Round 4-6: sc in each st  [16]
        \n\n
        Round 7: (dec, sc 2) x 4  [12]
        \n\n
        Round 8: (sc, dec) x 4  [8]
        \n\n
        Stuff the feet firmly. Keep adding a bit of fiberfill after every few rounds, stuffing the legs lightly.
        \n\n
        Round 9-24: sc in each st  [8]
        \n\n
        Sl st in next stitch. Cut the yarn, leaving a long yarn tail for sewing, and fasten off. Finish stuffing.
        \n\n\n
        TAIL
        \n\n
        Round 1: mr, sc 7  [7]
        \n\n
        Round 2-4: sc in each st  [7]
        \n\n
        Start stuffing the tail. Keep adding a bit of fiberfill after every few rounds, stuffing the tail lightly.
        \n\n
        Round 5-22: sc in each st  [7]
        \n\n
        Sl st in next stitch. Cut the yarn, leaving a long yarn tail for sewing, and fasten off. Finish stuffing.
        \n\n
        Sew the legs and tail to the body, placing them just above round three.
        \n\n
        Weave in the yarn tails and we\'re done\!
    </string>
</resources>