<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
    <string name="easy_crochet_beanie">
        Pattern by Sarah Stearns
        \n\n\n
        Supplies:
        \n\n
        \t+ Bulky Weight Yarn (200 yds were used for an Adult Medium)
        \n\n\t+ 6.5 mm Hook.
        \n\n\t+ Yarn Needle
        \n\n\t+ Stitch Markers
        \n\n\t+ Ruler or Tape Measure.
        \n\n\n\n
        Instructions:
        \n\n
        First, take your measurements.
        \n\n
        Row 1: Chain 36. Starting in the second chain from the hook, make 30 hdc. 5 sc. Turn. (35 sts)
        \n\n
        Row 2: Chain 1. Starting in the same (first) stitch, 5 sc blo, 30 hdc blo. Turn. (35 sts)
        \n\n
        Row 3: Chain 1. Starting in the same (first) stitch, 30 hdc blo, 4 sc blo, 1 sc. Turn. (35 sts)
        \n\n
        Repeat rows 2 and 3 until the crochet piece measures 20″ along the long edge – or your desired finished hat measurement that you calculated earlier.
        \n\n
        For my hat, I crocheted 36 rows total.
        \n\n
        Note: Take this measurement along the long edge of half-double crochet stitches, not the long edge with the single crochet stitches. A fabric measuring tape is useful here, since it\’s more flexible than a ruler.
        \n\n
        Finishing: Seam the sides.
        Hooray, you\’re almost finished! Now that it\’s time to seam the hat together, you have a choice between 2 seaming techniques.
        \n\n
        Option 1: The first option is to seam the sides of the hat together with a simple slip-stitch seam. To make a slip-stitch seam, you\’ll work a final row of slip-stitches through loops on both edges.
        To do this: First, fold the crocheted rectangle in half, right sides out, with the working row in front. Make a final row of slip stitches – but insert your hook through both the back loop of the working row and the loop of the starting chain.
        \n\n

        Option 2: Or, if you prefer, you can seam the sides together with a mattress stitch seam.
        Line up the two sides of the beanie, with the right sides facing outwards.
        Thread a yarn needle with the yarn tail that is about three times the length of the seam.
        Insert the needle under the first stitch on one side, then under the first stitch on the other side.
        Continue sewing the seam, moving back and forth. Try to match up the stitches as evenly as possible.
        Every few stitches, pull the yarn to close the seam. Try to keep an even tension, and don\’t over-tighten.
        Once you reach the end of the seam, weave in the yarn ends.
        \n\n
        Gather the top of the hat.
        Pull yarn through the last loop and trim a long yarn tail. Use the yarn tail and a darning needle to make long-running stitches along the top edge of the hat.
        Pull the yarn tail to gather the top edge of the hat, and pull it closed. You can knot the yarn tail to secure it. Weave in the ends.
    </string>
</resources>